Inventory of the Benjamin A. Rogge papers, 1945-2005
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and writings (Folder 10)
  - Haggarty-Smith Project, 1976 (Folder 10: 17)
- Speaking engagements, conferences, and meetings file (Folder 10-12)
  - Public Utility Executive Program, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1974-1975 (Folder 10: 18-19)
  - Mont Pèlerin Society general meeting, Hong Kong, 1978 (Folder 10: 20)
  - Edison Electric Institute Training Directors Institute, Denver, Colorado, 1978 (Folder 10: 21)
  - Graduate School of Banking, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 1976-1978 (Folder 10: 22)
  - Note about Robert Chitester, 1978 (Folder 10: 23)
  - "Symposium on Theory and Method in the Social Sciences," Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1978 (Folder 10: 24)
  - "Conference on Power Structure in American Education," San Francisco, California, 1978 (Folder 10: 25)
  - Scientech Club of Indianapolis, 1978 (Folder 10: 26)
  - Foundation for Economic Education, 1978 (Folder 10: 27)
  - Wabash discussion, 1978 (Folder 10: 28)
  - Confirmation Banquet, Lafayette, Indiana, 1978 (Folder 10: 29)
  - Warsaw Chamber of Commerce, Warsaw, Indiana, 1978 (Folder 10: 30)
  - Consolidated Natural Gas System, industrial marketing conference, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1978 (Folder 10: 31)
  - American Institute of Banking, Indianapolis, 1978 (Folder 10: 32)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1976-1978 (Folder 10: 33)
  - Lilly Endowment Project, 1978-1979 (Folder 10: 34)
  - The Taft School, Watertown, Connecticut, 1978-1979 (Folder 10: 35)
  - Industrial Heating Equipment Association, Key Largo, Florida, 1978-1979 (Folder 10: 36)
  - Princeton Telephone Company, Princeton, Indiana, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 1)
  - Administrative Management Society, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 2)
  - Junior League of Indianapolis, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 3)
  - Foundation for Economic Education, California, 1979 (Folder 11: 4)
  - Crawfordsville Lions' Club, 1978 (Folder 11: 5)
  - Liberty Fund meetings, London, 1978 (Folder 11: 6)
  - Michigan National Bank economic forecast luncheon, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 7)
  - Indiana Constructors Inc. Annual Convention, Hawaii, 1977-1979 (Folder 11: 8)
  - Florida, undated (Folder 11: 9)
  - Earhart Foundation meeting, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 10)
  - Liberty Fund, Law and Economics Seminar Center, John H. Moore, University of Miami, 1978 (Folder 11: 11)
  - Hillsdale College, Michigan, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 12)
  - Vanderbilt economic forum, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 13)
  - Hastings College, Award Convocation, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 14)
  - Foundation for Economic Education annual meeting, Tarrytown, New York, 1979 (Folder 11: 15)
  - Lilly Corporate Credit education meeting, Turkey Run State Park, Indiana, 1979 (Folder 11: 16)
  - Brenton First National Bank, Davenport, Iowa, 1979 (Folder 11: 17)
  - Liberty Fund Socratic seminar, "The Intellectuals and Socialism,", 1979 (Folder 11: 18)
  - Irving Kristol, 1979 (Folder 11: 19)
  - Edison Electric Institute Executive Management Program, Hershey, Pennsylvania, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 20)
  - Earhart Foundation, 1979 (Folder 11: 21)
  - IBM executive seminar, Sands Point, New York, 1979 (Folder 11: 22)
  - Philadelphia Society, Chicago, Illinois, 1979 (Folder 11: 23)
  - Financial Executives Institute, north central area conference, Marco Island, Florida, 1979 (Folder 11: 24)
  - Illinois Press Association, Peoria, Illinois, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 25)
  - Foundation for Economic Education seminar, California, 1979 (Folder 11: 26)
  - Rosary College Biennial Career Night Dinner, River Forest, Illinois, 1979 (Folder 11: 27)
  - Rubber Manufacturers Association, 1979 (Folder 11: 28)
  - Executive Development Program, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1979 (Folder 11: 29)
  - IBM, Advanced Management School, Sands Point, New York, 1979 (Folder 11: 30)
  - North Central Electric Association, Okoboji, Iowa, 1979 (Folder 11: 31)
  - Industrial Revolution film premier, 1979 (Folder 11: 32)
  - Summer Institute in Political Economy, Hillsdale College, Michigan, 1979 (Folder 11: 33)
  - Pittsburgh Financial Executives Institute, 1979 (Folder 11: 34)
  - Mont Pèlerin Society regional meeting, Madrid, Spain, 1979 (Folder 11: 35)
  - Pulliam Fellows, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1979 (Folder 11: 36)
  - Young President's Organization, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1979 (Folder 12: 1)
  - First Boston Corporation, New York, 1979 (Folder 12: 2)
  - Iowa Utilities management conference, Des Moines, 1979-1980 (Folder 12: 3)
  - Ashland Chemical Company Accounting Department seminar, Salt Fork, Ohio, 1979 (Folder 12: 4)
  - First Midland Bank & Trust Company, Michigan, 1978-1979 (Folder 12: 5)
  - Nebraska Economics and Business Association (NEBA), Hastings, 1979 (Folder 12: 6)
  - South Dakota Bankers Association economic seminar, 1978-1979 (Folder 12: 7)
- Education file (Folder 11-12)
  - Liberty Fund Education seminar transcripts, 1971 (Folder 11: 8-11)
  - Liberty Fund seminars, 1962-1972 (Folder 11: 12)
    Includes seminar summaries
  - Academic Truths and Frauds by Gottfried Dietze, 1971-1972 (Folder 11: 13)
  - Goodrich seminar, Liberty Fund (1971) and general materials, 1961-1972 (Folder 13: 1-3)
    Includes speeches and writings Rogge
  - Goodrich source material, 1971-1972 (Folder 13: 4)
  - Institute for Humane Studies seminar papers, 1972 (Folder 13: 5)
  - Liberty Fund Education seminar transcripts, 1971 (Folder 14: 1)
  - "The Educated Man" by Eliseo Vivass, 1971 (Folder 14: 2)
- Speaking engagements, conferences, and meetings file (Folder 14)
  - Almost "20-20" Foresight conference transcripts, 1971 (Folder 14: 3-5)
    Includes dialogue between Pierre Goodrich, Rogge, and others
- Education file (Folder 14)
  - Financing higher education, 1957-1958 (Folder 14: 6)
  - Liberty Fund Education seminar, correspondence (March 28-April 30, 1971), 1970-1971 (Folder 14: 7)
  - Comments on education memorandum by Pierre Goodrich, 1968-1969 (Folder 14: 8)
  - Liberty Fund Education seminar (November 26-28, 1971), 1959, 1970-1971 (Folder 14: 9)
- Speeches and writings (Folder 15)
  - "Financing Higher Education in the United States,", 1958-1960 (Folder 15: 1)
  - Published articles, 1974-1978 (Folder 15: 2)
  - A Tese de Prebisch, 1959 (Folder 15: 3)
  - "The Businessman" and "The Intellectual and the Man of Affairs,", 1965, 1978 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Letter to the editor of the Indianapolis News, 1973 (Folder 15: 5)
- Correspondence (Folder 15)
  - John V. Van Sickle, 1962-1971 (Folder 15: 6-7)
- Subject file (Folder 16)
  - Radical materials, 1960-1973 (Folder 16: 1)
    Includes "Bank Structure and the Bank Customer" by Rogge
- Speeches and writings (Folder 16)
  - "An Economist's Look at Bank Holding Companies" pamphlet, 1973-1976 (Folder 16: 2)
  - Testimony of Rogge, undated (Folder 16: 3)
- Biographical file (Folder 16)
  - Rogge obituaries, 1980 (Folder 16: 4)
  - Nomination for position of dean at Willamette University, 1971 (Folder 16: 5)
- Subject file (Folder 16)
  - Herbert Hoover Presidential Library Association Essay Contest, 1973 (Folder 16: 6)
- Printed matter and writings by others (Folder 16)
  - "The Financing and Administration of Education" by John V. Van Sickle, 1960 (Folder 16: 7)
  - "Clichés of Socialism" by Foundation for Economic Education, and miscellaneous, 1973, undated (Folder 16: 8)
  - Iron and Steel Transforming Industries in Selected Latin American Countries, Economic Commission for Latin America, 1955 (Folder 16: 9)
  - Writings by others, 1975-1977, undated (Folder 16: 10-11)
    Includes notes and writings on Adam Smith
  - Adam Smith typescript, undated (Folder 16: 12)
- Speeches and writings (Folder 17)
  - "Keynesian Policy,", circa 1955 (Folder 17: 1)
  - "The Businessman and Free Enterprise,", 1975 (Folder 17: 2)
  - "Alleged Causes I: Corporate Monopolies,", undated (Folder 17: 3)
  - "Economics Education in the Schools," Yale Conservative Club, 1967 (Folder 17: 4)
  - "Paradise in Posey Country,", undated (Folder 17: 5)
  - "The New Conservatism," speech, Nassau Club, 6 December 1961 (Folder 17: 6)
  - "Is Economic Freedom Possible?", undated (Folder 17: 7)
  - "The American Economy in the 1980s," outline, undated (Folder 17: 8)
- Writings by others (Folder 16)
  - "The Easy Chair" by John Fischer, 1970 (Folder 17: 9)
- Speeches and writings (Folder 17)
  - "Clichés of Socialism,", undated (Folder 17: 10)
  - Indianapolis Star column clippings (Folder 17)
    - "Putty in the Hands of Image Makers,", 19 October 1980 (Folder 17: 11)
    - "Intellectuals' Curse of Capitalism,", 5 October 1980 (Folder 17: 12)
    - "Of Turnips and Energy Scarcity,", 28 September 1980 (Folder 17: 13)
    - "Barriers on the Road to Employment,", 21 September 1980 (Folder 17: 14)
    - "Debating the Gold Standard,", 14 September 1980 (Folder 17: 15)
    - "A Postponed Day of Reckoning,", 7 September 1980 (Folder 17: 16)
      Includes correspondence
  - "An Economist's Look at Bank Holding Companies,", undated (Folder 17: 17)
  - "Well, So You're a College Graduate," commencement speech, Hastings College, 1980 (Folder 17: 18)
  - "Commencement Address," Hastings College, 1980 (Folder 17: 19)
  - Papers on banking, 1973, undated (Folder 17: 20)
  - "FEE: Success of Failure?" speech, FEE's 25th anniversary in Tarrytown, New York, 17 May 1971 (Folder 17: 21)
  - "Exeter Talk,", 16 February 1964 (Folder 17: 22)
  - "Education in a Free Society," co-written with Pierre Goodrich, undated (Folder 17: 23)
  - "The Economy," speech, National Association of Plastics Distributors Convention, August 1973 (Folder 17: 24)
  - "Economic Outlook,", 10 March 1979 (Folder 17: 25)
  - "Economic Outlook,", February 1980 (Folder 17: 26)
  - "Economic Forecast,", June 1977 (Folder 17: 27)
  - "The Outlook for the American Economy,", 1971, undated (Folder 17: 28-29)
- Writings by others (Folder 17)
  - "Is Keynes Defunct?" by Albert L. Kraus, 1968 (Folder 17: 30)
  - "Monetary and Fiscal Actions: A Test of Their Relative Importance in Economic Stabilization" by Leonall C. Anderson and Jerry L. Jordan, November 1968 (Folder 17: 31)
- Speeches and writings (Folder 17-18)
  - Summary of B. A. Rogge's Remarks on the Long-Run Outlook for the American Economy, undated (Folder 17: 32)
  - "Monopoly of Competition Policy?" Brussels, 1974 (Folder 17: 33)
  - The Businessman," Chapel speech, 8 April 1965 (Folder 17: 34)
  - Chapel speech, 10 April 1969 (Folder 17: 35)
  - Speech in honor of Charles D. La Follette on his retirement, 28 October 1977 (Folder 17: 36)
  - "Indiana Bar Speech,", June 1964 (Folder 17: 37)
  - "The Prebisch Thesis Revisited,", undated (Folder 18: 1)
  - "Read's 70th Birthday," speech, 4 October 1968 (Folder 18: 2)
  - "Voluntary Organization in the Free Society,", undated (Folder 18: 3)
  - Summary of Rogge's comments before the Wisconsin Bankers' Association, 18 June 1974 (Folder 18: 4)
  - "Park-Tudor Commencement Address,", 2 June 1972 (Folder 18: 5)
  - "The Power of Tomorrow: Whither FEE?" speech at Foundation for Economic Education (FEE) trustees meeting, 18 November 1979 (Folder 18: 6)
- Speaking engagements, conferences, and meetings file (Folder 18)
  - "Revelation," Goodrich seminar, Liberty Fund, 1968-1969 (Folder 18: 7)
- Speeches and writings (Folder 18)
  - "Tenure,", 16 February 1972 (Folder 18: 8)
  - "Who's to Blame?", January 1961 (Folder 18: 9)
  - "What Price Education?", 1 May 1959 (Folder 18: 10)
  - "What Are the Duties of the State?" speech, Philadelphia Society, 6 October 1967 (Folder 18: 11)
  - "Student Power and All That,", 1968 (Folder 18: 12)
  - "Some Recent Literature on Regional Economics," review in The Review of Economics and Statistics, 1956 (Folder 18: 13)
  - "Responsibility," The Hoosier Conservative, 1966 (Folder 18: 14)
  - "Some Recent Literature on Regional Economics,", 1956 (Folder 18: 15)
  - "Should the U.S. be in Viet Nam?", 1969 (Folder 18: 16)
- Writings by others (Folder 18)
  - "Prometheus Bound" by George Gilder, 1978 (Folder 18: 17)
  - On Power by Bertrand de Jouvenel, undated (Folder 18: 18)
- Speaking engagements, conferences, and meetings file (Folder 18-20)
  - Education (Folder 18-20)
    - Papers for "Conference on the Power Structure in American Education,", 1978 (Folder 18: 19)
    - Liberty Fund Socratic seminar, "Natural Law and Natural Rights,", October 1978 (Folder 18: 20)
    - "Revelation," Goodrich seminar, Liberty Fund, transcript, 1969 (Folder 19: 1)
    - Ethics, Power, and National Defense seminar, Liberty Fund and National Strategy Information Center, 1972 (Folder 19: 2)
    - Goodrich seminar, 1964 (Folder 19: 3)
    - Education in a Free Society, George Pearson, 1970-1973 (Folder 19: 4-5)
    - "Conference on the Ideology of Public Schooling," Cleveland, Ohio, 1975 (Folder 19: 6)
    - Education seminar, George Pearson, Institute for Humane Studies, 1974 (Folder 20: 1)
  - Seminar on Power, Liberty Fund, 1965-1967 (Folder 20: 2)
  - Gold clause conference, Key Biscayne, Florida, 1974-1975 (Folder 20: 3)
    Includes paper by Milton Friedman
  - Socratic seminar, The American Constitution, case readings, 1976 (Folder 20: 4)
    Includes photocopies of materials published in 1800s and 1900s
- Various writings by others, photocopies and bibliography, undated (Folder 20: 5)
- Mont Pèlerin Society (Folder 21)
  - 15th meeting, Stresa, Italy, 1965 (Folder 21: 1)
  - Meeting, Munich, Germany, 1970 (Folder 21: 2)
  - Meeting, Vichy, France, 1967 (Folder 21: 3)
  - Meeting, Belgium, Germany, 1971-1974 (Folder 21: 4)
  - Ibero-American regional meeting, Guatemala, 1973 (Folder 21: 5)
- "Why Liberty?" by Pierre Goodrich, read at September 1958 meeting (Folder 22: 1)
  Includes photocopies of various writings by others
- Organizations file (Folder 22-25:)
  Includes correspondence, printed matter, and clippings
  - William Volker Fund, 1964, 1973 (Folder 22: 2)
  - Winchester Special Loan and Scholarship Fund, 1965-1979 (Folder 22: 3)
  - World Research, Inc., 1976-1980 (Folder 22: 4)
    Includes photographs
  - Young Americans for Freedom (YAF), 1970-1978 (Folder 22: 5)
  - Young Libertarian Alliance, 1975-1976 (Folder 22: 6)
  - Indiana Committee for the Humanities, 1973 (Folder 22: 7)
  - Alternative Educational Foundation, Inc., 1977-1980 (Folder 22: 8)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 1961-1967 (Folder 22: 9)
  - American Conservative Union, 1965 (Folder 22: 10)
  - American Economics Association, 1962-1974 (Folder 22: 11)
  - American Enterprise Institute, 1971-1975 (Folder 22: 12)
  - American Management Associations, 1978 (Folder 22: 13)
  - Cato Institute, 1978-1980 (Folder 22: 14)
  - Center for Liberation Studies, 1976 (Folder 22: 15)
  - Center for the Defense of Free Enterprise, 1979 (Folder 23: 1)
    Includes interview of Rogge by Greg McDonald
  - Center for the Study of American Business, 1976-1977 (Folder 23: 2)
  - Center for the Study of Market Alternatives, undated (Folder 23: 3)
  - The Children's Museum, Indianapolis, economic exhibit, 1978-1979 (Folder 23: 4)
  - Circulo de la Libertad, 1978 (Folder 23: 5)
  - The Citizens Cabinet, 1977 (Folder 23: 6)
  - Citizens for a New Prosperity, 1971 (Folder 23: 7)
  - Committee for Monetary Research & Education, Inc., 1973, undated (Folder 23: 8)
  - Council for a Competitive Economy, 1980 (Folder 23: 9)
  - Economic Club of Indianapolis, circa 1980 (Folder 23: 10)
  - Eisenhower Memorial Scholarship Foundation, 1979 (Folder 23: 11)
  - The Exchange, newsletters, 1968-1975 (Folder 23: 12)
  - The Foundation for Freedom, 1979-1980 (Folder 23: 13)
  - Foundation for Research in Economics and Education, 1977-1978 (Folder 23: 14)
  - The Fraser Institute, 1976 (Folder 23: 15)
  - Free Market Education Foundation, 1978-1980 (Folder 23: 16)
  - Free Society Association, 1965 (Folder 23: 17)
  - Freedom School, 1963-1966 (Folder 23: 18)
  - Gold Bond Council, 1978 (Folder 23: 19)
  - Gold Bond Council, 1978 (Folder 23: 19)
  - Group for the Study of Radical Political Economics (Papadjimas), 1973 (Folder 23: 20)
  - Heritage Foundation, 1978-1980 (Folder 23: 21)
  - History of Economics Society, 1977 (Folder 23: 22)
  - Hoosier Organization of Professional Educators for Montgomery Country Affiliate of the National Association of Professional Educators, undated (Folder 23: 23)
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, 1977 (Folder 23: 24)
  - Indiana Academy of Social Sciences, 1956-1959 (Folder 23: 25)
  - Indiana Conservative Club, 1957-1959, 1978 (Folder 23: 26)
  - Indiana Council for Economic Education (ICEE), 1973-1979 (Folder 23: 27)
  - Indiana Young Americans for Freedom, 1977 (Folder 23: 28)
  - International Freedom Academy (INFRA), undated (Folder 23: 29)
  - Institute of Economic Affairs, 1971-1975 (Folder 23: 30)
  - Institute for Human Rights Research, 1979 (Folder 23: 31)
  - Institute for Humane Studies, 1970-1980 (Folder 24: 1)
  - Institute for the Study of Market Agriculture, 1978-1979 (Folder 24: 2)
  - International Institute for Economic Research, 1971-1974 (Folder 24: 3)
  - Intercollegiate Studies Institute (ISI), 1972-1980 (Folder 24: 4-5)
  - Invisible Hand Society, 1975-1977 (Folder 24: 6)
  - Joint Council on Economic Education, 1978 (Folder 24: 7)
  - Lilly Endowment, 1966-1979 (Folder 24: 8)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research, Inc., 1979 (Folder 24: 9)
  - National Journalism Center, 1979 (Folder 24: 10)
  - National Legal Center for the Public Interest, 1977 (Folder 24: 11)
  - National Right to Work Committee, 1978 (Folder 24: 12)
  - National Taxpayers Union, 1979 (Folder 24: 13)
  - New Individualist Review (Ralph Raico), 1965, undated (Folder 24: 14)
  - Nichol's School, 1970, undated (Folder 25: 1)
  - Pacific Academy for Advanced Studies, 1978-1980 (Folder 25: 2)
  - Philadelphia Society, 1966-1980 (Folder 25: 3)
  - Relm and Earhart Foundations, 1972-1980 (Folder 25: 4)
  - Research and Development, Boy Scouts of America, 1972 (Folder 25: 5)
  - United States Industrial Council, 1978 (Folder 25: 6)
  - Urban Institute, 1978 (Folder 25: 7)
    Includes "Ethnic Minorities Research Project Prospectus" and correspondence with Thomas Sowell
- Subject file (Folder 25-28)
  Includes correspondence, clippings, printed matter, notes, and speeches and writings by Rogge.
  - Extra copies, 1961-1971 (Folder 25: 8-9)
  - Economic freedom; private property, 1968-1971 (Folder 25: 10)
  - Loans, 1973 (Folder 25: 11)
  - Negros and unions, 1968-1972 (Folder 25: 12)
  - General property, 1972 (Folder 25: 13)
  - General market examples, 1970-1973 (Folder 26: 1)
  - Intervention, 1970-1972 (Folder 26: 2)
  - Licensing, fair trade, etc., 1975, undated (Folder 26: 3)
  - Welfare, social security, 1961-1976 (Folder 26: 4)
  - Schumpeter, survival of capitalism, intellectuals, 1971-1975 (Folder 26: 5)
    Includes writing by Rogge
  - Will capitalism survive, 1974-1978 (Folder 26: 6)
  - Competition, 1966-1979 (Folder 26: 7-8)
  - Trade unions, 1970-1973 (Folder 26: 9)
  - General freedom, 1958-1972 (Folder 26: 10)
  - FDA, 1970 (Folder 26: 11)
  - Adam Smith lecture, 1975-1977 (Folder 27: 1)
    Includes drafts by Rogge
  - Japan, 1971-1978 (Folder 27: 2)
  - Italy, France, etc., 1976-1980 (Folder 27: 3)
  - Sweden, 1970-1978 (Folder 27: 4)
  - Compensation systems, 1965-1975 (Folder 27: 5)
  - Utopia, 1977 (Folder 27: 6)
  - Brazil, 1964-1970 (Folder 27: 7)
  - Pyramid examples, 1974 (Folder 27: 8)
  - Cuba, 1969-1971 (Folder 27: 9)
  - England, 1973-1979 (Folder 27: 10)
  - Africa, 1967-1979 (Folder 27: 11)
  - Pollution, 1971-1973 (Folder 27: 12)
  - India, Hong Kong, etc., 1966-1976 (Folder 27: 13)
  - Germany, 1974 (Folder 27: 14)
  - Eastern Europe, 1967-1976 (Folder 28: 1)
  - South America, 1965-1977 (Folder 28: 2)
  - Pollution, 1972-1977 (Folder 28: 3)
  - Competition, 1961-1975 (Folder 28: 4)
  - China, 1967-1979 (Folder 28: 5)
- Speeches and writings (Folder 28)
  - Businessmen and free enterprise, 1975-1977 (Folder 28: 6)
- Subject file (Folder 28-30)
  - Children, 1975 (Folder 28: 7)
  - Competitive systems, USSR, 1960-1980 (Folder 29: 1)
    Includes syllabus for Economics 18
  - Energy, 1972-1977 (Folder 29: 2)
  - Minimum wage, child labor, 1947-1976 (Folder 29: 3)
  - Consumerism, 1971-1976 (Folder 29: 4)
  - Demands for wages, 1970-1971 (Folder 30: 1)
  - General market philosophy, 1945-1970 (Folder 30: 2)
  - Comparative systems, second level, 1968-1973 (Folder 30: 3)
  - Underdeveloped countries, 1974 (Folder 30: 4)
  - Book requests, 1978-1980 (Folder 30: 5)
  - Inventory of the Ludwig Von Mises papers, 1978 (Folder 30: 6)
- Speeches and writings (Folder 30-31)
  - General, 1965-1971, undated (Folder 30: 7)
    Includes compact sound cassette of letter to Rogge from Fred James
  - General, 1963-1975, undated (Folder 30: 8-9)
  - Viet Nam speech, research materials, and general speeches, 1956-1970 (Folder 30: 10)
  - Urban renewal and P through W, 1957-1968, undated (Folder 31: 1)
  - Commencement speeches, 1959 (Folder 31: 2)
  - "Race and Economics,", undated (Folder 31: 3)
- Subject file (Folder 31)
  - Direct controls, 1971-1974 (Folder 31: 4)
    Includes photocopy of speech from 1922
  - Steel imports, 1977 (Folder 31: 5)
  - Capital shortage?, 1975-1977 (Folder 31: 6)
- Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Folder 31: 7)
- Speeches and writings (Folder 31)
  - "Who's to Blame?", 1960-1962 (Folder 31: 8)
  - "Economic Outlook,", 1968, undated (Folder 31: 9)
  - M through N, 1956-1967 (Folder 31: 10)
    Includes outline of speech for Mont Pèlerin Society
- Subject file (Folder 31-32)
  - Economic outlook, basic, 1977 (Folder 31: 11)
  - Housing, cities, slums, 1966-1978 (Folder 31: 12)
  - General, 1972-1980 (Folder 32: 1)
    Includes speech outline
  - East-West trade, 1964-1973 (Folder 32: 2)
- Speeches and writings (Folder 32-33)
  - United Fund, FEE seminars, "The Case for Economic Freedom,", 1963-1965, undated (Folder 32: 3)
  - Writings, research materials, and notes, 1958-1968 (Folder 32: 4-5)
  - Can Capitalism Survive?, reviews, 1978 (Folder 32: 6)
    Includes interviews of John Kenneth Galbraith and Milton Friedman
  - Speeches, original manuscripts, 1961-1969, undated (Folder 32: 7)
  - A through G, 1955-1968, undated (Folder 33)
  - Reprints, 1974-1976 (Folder 33)
- Testimony of Rogge before the Public Utilities Commission of Ohio, undated (Folder 33)
- Clippings, printed matter, notes, 1962-1980, undated (Folder 33)
- Indiana Public Service Commission (Folder 34)
  See also box 46
  - East Indiana Telephone Company, 1958-1959 (Folder 34: 1)
  - Midwest Telephone Company, 1958 (Folder 34: 2)
  - Princeton Telephone Company, 1972-1973 (Folder 34: 3)
  - Sullivan Telephone Company, circa 1956 (Folder 34: 4)
  - Testimony of Rogge, United Telephone Company of the West, undated (Folder 34: 5)
  - Lafayette Water Works, Perry testimony, 1958, undated (Folder 34: 6)
  - Citizens Telephone Company of Clay County, 1957 (Folder 34: 7)
  - Testimony of Rogge, Princeton Telephone Company, undated (Folder 34: 8)
- Industrial Revolution, Liberty Fund film, scripts, teachers' guides, evaluations, 1978-1979 (Folder 34: 9-10)
- Writings by others (Folder 34)
  - American Ethnic Groups, edited by Thomas Sowell, 1977 (Folder 34: 11)
  - Reality's Golden Mean by Nels Hultberg, 1978 (Folder 34: 12)
- Speeches and writings by Rogge, 1966-1976, undated (Folder 35)
  Includes review of Can Capitalism Survive?, book chapters on economics and race, and writings on Latin America and Vietnam
- Industrial Revolution, Liberty Fund film, scripts, 1978 (Folder 35)
- Award ceremonies honoring Rogge, 1978-1979 (Folder 35)
- Clippings, printed matter, notes, 1962-1980 (Folder 35)
  Includes pamphlet for Free to Choose
- Speeches and writings by Rogge, 1974-1978 (Folder 36)
- Writings by others, 1979 (Folder 36)
- Award ceremonies honoring Rogge, 1978-1979 (Folder 36)
- Testimony by Rogge, undated (Folder 36)